(Music)
(موسيقى)
These bees are in my backyard in Berkeley, California.
توجد هذه النحلات في فناء داري في (بيركلي) في كاليفورنيا
Until last year, I'd never kept bees before,
حتى السنة الفائتة، لم أكن أحتفظ بالنحل
but National Geographic asked me to photograph a story about them,
لكن (ناشونال جيوغرافيك) طلبت تصوير وثائقي عنها
and I decided, to be able to take compelling images,
ولكي أستطيع التقاط الصور المطلوبة
I should start keeping bees myself.
قررت أن أقوم بتربية النحل
And as you may know,
وكما تعلمون
bees pollinate one third of our food crops,
يلقح النحل ثلث محاصيلنا الغذائية
and lately they've been having a really hard time.
ويمر النحل مؤخراً بفترات صعبة
So as a photographer, I wanted to explore what this problem really looks like.
أردت كمصور أن أكتشف المشكلة التي يواجهها النحل
So I'm going to show you what I found over the last year.
سأقوم بإطلاعكم على اكتشافاتي على مدار السنة الماضية
This furry little creature
هذا المخلوق الفروي الصغير
is a fresh young bee halfway emerged from its brood cell,
عبارة عن نحلة صغيرة انبثقت لتوها من خليتها الحاضنة
and bees right now are dealing with several different problems,
ويواجه النحل الآن عدة مشاكل مختلفة
including pesticides, diseases, and habitat loss,
بما في ذلك المبيدات الحشرية والأمراض وفقدان الموطن
but the single greatest threat is a parasitic mite from Asia,
لكن التهديد الأكبر يتمثل بالسوس الطفيلي من آسيا
Varroa destructor.
مدمر الفاروا
And this pinhead-sized mite crawls onto young bees
ينقضّ هذا السوس البالغ الصغر على النحلات الصغيرة
and sucks their blood.
ويمص دمائها
This eventually destroys a hive
هذا سيؤدي لتدمير الخلية
because it weakens the immune system of the bees,
لأنه يضعف الجهاز المناعي لدى النحل
and it makes them more vulnerable to stress and disease.
ويجعلها أكثر حساسية للتوتر والأمراض
Now, bees are the most sensitive
تكون حساسية النحل في أشدها
when they're developing inside their brood cells,
عندما تنمو داخل الخلايا الحاضنة
and I wanted to know what that process really looks like,
وأردت أن أطلع على مراحل نمو النحل
so I teamed up with a bee lab at U.C. Davis
لذا أنشأت فريقاً في مختبر (يو سي دافيس)
and figured out how to raise bees in front of a camera.
واكتشفت كيف ينشأ النحل أمام الكاميرا
I'm going to show you the first 21 days of a bee's life
سترون الآن أول 21 يوماً من حياة النحلة
condensed into 60 seconds.
في 60 ثانية
This is a bee egg as it hatches into a larva,
هذه بيضة نحلة تنفقس وتعطي يرقة
and those newly hatched larvae swim around their cells
وهذه اليرقات تسبح حول خلاياها
feeding on this white goo that nurse bees secrete for them.
وتقتات على هذه المادة البيضاء التي ترشح عن النحل
Then, their head and their legs slowly differentiate
من ثم يبرز رأسها وأقدامها ببطء
as they transform into pupae.
بينما تتحول إلى شرانق
Here's that same pupation process,
هذه عملية التشرنق ذاتها
and you can actually see the mites running around in the cells.
كما يمكنكم رؤية العت ينتشر حول الخلايا
Then the tissue in their body reorganizes
ثم ينتظم النسيج في جسدها من جديد
and the pigment slowly develops in their eyes.
ويتطور الصبغ ببطء في عينيها
The last step of the process is their skin shrivels up
وفي الخطوة الأخيرة من العملية تذوب البشرة
and they sprout hair.
وينمو الشعر
(Music)
(موسيقى)
So -- (Applause)
أذاً.. -- (تصفيق)
As you can see halfway through that video,
كما ترون في هذا الفيديو
the mites were running around on the baby bees,
كان العت ينتشر حول صغار النحل
and the way that beekeepers typically manage these mites
وما يفعله النحَّالون للتعامل مع العت
is they treat their hives with chemicals.
أنهم يعالجون خلايا النحل بالمواد الكيماوية
In the long run, that's bad news,
هذه أخبار سيئة على المدى البعيد
so researchers are working on finding alternatives
لذا يعمل الباحثون على إيجاد البدائل
to control these mites.
للحد من انتشار العت
This is one of those alternatives.
وهذه إحدى البدائل
It's an experimental breeding program at the USDA Bee Lab in Baton Rouge,
إنه برنامج تربية تجريبي في مختبرات للنحل لوزارة الفلاحة الأمريكية في (باتون روج)
and this queen and her attendant bees are part of that program.
وهذه الملكة ونحلاتها الحاضرة هم جزء من هذا البرنامج
Now, the researchers figured out
وقد اكتشف العلماء
that some of the bees have a natural ability to fight mites,
أن بعض النحلات لديها قدرة طبيعية على مكافحة العت
so they set out to breed a line of mite-resistant bees.
لذا فقد شرعوا بتربية نوع من النحلات المقاومة للعت
This is what it takes to breed bees in a lab.
هذا ما تحتاجه لتنشئة النحل في المختبر
The virgin queen is sedated
يتم تخدير الملكة العذراء
and then artificially inseminated using this precision instrument.
ثم تتعرض لتخصيب اصطناعي بواسطة آلة دقيقة
Now, this procedure allows the researchers
يتيح هذا الإجراء للباحثين
to control exactly which bees are being crossed,
التحكم بتحديد النحلات التي يتم تهجينها
but there's a tradeoff in having this much control.
لكن ثمة مخاطر لهذا الكم من التحكم
They succeeded in breeding mite-resistant bees,
حيث ينجحون في تنشئة نحلات مقاومة للعت
but in that process, those bees started to lose traits
لكن هذه العملية تفقد النحل بعض المزايا
like their gentleness and their ability to store honey,
مثل ليونتها وقدرتها على تخزين العسل
so to overcome that problem,
وللتغلب على هذه المشكلة
these researchers are now collaborating with commercial beekeepers.
يقوم الباحثون بالتعاون مع نحالين تجاريين
This is Bret Adee opening one of his 72,000 beehives.
ها هو (بريت أدي) يفتح إحدى خلايا النحل البالغ عددها 72,000
He and his brother run the largest beekeeping operation in the world,
يدير وشقيقه أكبر عملية تنشأة للنحل في العالم
and the USDA is integrating their mite-resistant bees into his operation
ويقوم مختبر وزارة الفلاحة بدمج النحلات المقاومة للعت بعمليته
with the hope that over time,
آملين أنه مع الوقت
they'll be able to select the bees that are not only mite-resistant
سيتمكنون من اختيار النحلات التي لا تتصف بمقاومتها للعت وحسب
but also retain all of these qualities that make them useful to us.
بل وتمتلك جميع هذه الصفات التي تجعلها مفيدة لنا
And to say it like that
لكن وجهة النظر هذه
makes it sound like we're manipulating and exploiting bees,
تجعل الأمر يبدو وكأننا نتلاعب بالنحل ونستغله
and the truth is, we've been doing that for thousands of years.
والحقيقة أننا لطالما اتبعنا هذا النهج لآلاف السنوات
We took this wild creature and put it inside of a box,
نأخذ هذا المخلوق البري ونضعه داخل صندوق
practically domesticating it,
ونقوم بتدجينه بطريقة عملية
and originally that was so that we could harvest their honey,
ومن ثم نجمع العسل الناتج من النحل
but over time we started losing our native pollinators,
لكن مع الوقت بدأنا نفقد ملقحاتنا المحلية
our wild pollinators,
والملقحات البرية
and there are many places now where those wild pollinators
وثمة الكثير من الأماكن حيث لم تعد الملقحات البرية
can no longer meet the pollination demands of our agriculture,
قادرة على تحقيق مطالب التلقيح في زراعتنا
so these managed bees have become an integral part of our food system.
وقد أصبحت هذه النحلات جزءاً تكاملياً في نظامنا الغذائي
So when people talk about saving bees,
وعندما يتحدث الناس عن إنقاذ النحل
my interpretation of that
هذا يعني بالنسبة لي
is we need to save our relationship to bees,
أننا بحاجة لإنقاذ علاقتنا بالنحل
and in order to design new solutions,
ولكي نبتكر حلولاً جديدة
we have to understand the basic biology of bees
فيجب أن نفهم البيولوجية الأساسية للنحل
and understand the effects of stressors that we sometimes cannot see.
وأن ندرك آثارالضغوطات التي يتعذر علينا رؤيتها أحياناً
In other words, we have to understand bees up close.
بمعنى آخر، يجب فهم طبيعة النحل عن كثب
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)